Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - B. Collections of Printed music (Box 66, Box S/62, Box S/63, Box S/64, Box S/65, Box S/66)
    - Collections, Box 4: Twelve works bound together in a single hard-cover volume, of which the first ten are works by Musorgskiĭ, M.; items are listed in the order in which they appear. (Box 66, Box S/65, Box S/66)
      - Musorgskiĭ, Modest Petrovich
        - Chanson d'enfant. [=Dietskaia piesenka; Children's song.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 5928; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65d)
        - Kallistrate. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 5948; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65e)
        - Aux bords du Don. [=Po nad Donom sad tsvietet.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5945; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65f)
        - Berceuse du paysan. [=Spi, usni, krest'ianskiĭ syn.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 5935; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65g)
        - La nuit. [=Noch'; Night.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 5936; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65h)
        - Vision. [=Vidien'e.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5944; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65i)
        - Doucement planait une âme. [=Gornimi tikho letiela dusha nebesami.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5940; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65j)
        - Trouble. [=Razsievaetsia, razstupaetsia.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 5943; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65k)
        - Hopak. [La foire de Sorochintsi: Gopak.] London: J. & W. Chester, 1916., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. M.P.B.2709.; Edition: M.P. Belaïeff; Language note: French; Language note: English (Box-folder S/65l)
      - Stravinsky, Igor
        - A song of the dew, op. 6, no. 2. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 36200.; Language note: French; Language note: English (Box-folder S/65)
      - Tchaikovsky, Pëtr Il'ich
        - Primiren'e. St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 3046.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/65)
        - Album klasiků. Prague: M. Urbánek, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 195 p.; Plate no. M.U.25.; p. 75-78 not present; Contains sparse annotations in pencil; Contains works of W.A. Mozart, L. van Beethoven, C. Loewe, F. Schubert, F. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, R. Schumann.; Language note: Czech (Box-folder S/66o)
      - [Unidentified]
        - [Collection of piano works.] [New York]: G. Schirmer, 1897., Solo piano; score; 101 p.; Plate no. 13500.; Incomplete publication data: cover and title pages not present.
        - Neuvième album Francis Salabert. Paris: F. Salabert, 1926., Solo piano; score; 62 p.; Plate no. E.A.S.4158. (Box-folder 66/2)
        - Album russe: 36 beliebte Werke russischer Komponisten. Hamburg: A.J. Benjamin, n.d., Solo piano; score; 142 p.; Plate no. A.J.B.3496, 3514, 3519; plates are mostly unnumbered.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 66/3)
        - Sept chants populaires. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, [1910]., Voice and piano; score; 30 p.; Plate no. 34868 through 34874.; Hebrew transliterated; Language note: Limousin dialect; Language note: Spanish; Language note: Hebrew; Language note: English; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 66/4)
        - Collection de ballets et fragments célèbres Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Solo piano; score; 17 p.; Specific works not indicated.; Plate no. A.C.2794. (Box-folder 66/5)
        - Les maîtres musiciens de la renaissance française, v. 1: Danceries. Paris: A. Leduc, 1908., Four part instrumental arrangement and keyboard reduction; score; 115 p.; Plate no. A.L.14052.; Contains dedication to Diaghilev from the editor, inside front cover page. (Box-folder 66/6)
        - The Russian song books, v. 1. London: J.W. Chester, 1917., Voice and piano; score; 25 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.3745.; Language note: English; Language note: French (Box-folder 66/7)
        - The Russian song books, v. 2. London: J.W. Chester, 1917., Voice and piano; score; 25 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.3746.; Language note: English; Language note: French (Box-folder 66/8)
      - Glinka, Mikhaĭl
        - Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies. [=Collection of musical pieces.] St. Petersburg: [s.n.], 1839., Solo piano; score; 26 p.; Contains: Haberbier, E., Valse Laskowsky, J., Valse Dargomyzhskiĭ, A., Le rêve de la Esméralda Glinka, M., Valse Glinka, M., Thème de l'opéra Faniska de Cherubini (Box-folder 66/9)
  - C. Miscellaneous/unidentified (Box 67)
    - Unidentified fragments of printed music; 8 items. (Box-folder 67/1)
    - Covers of printed music containing autograph inscriptions; 5 items. (Box-folder 67/2)
    - Covers of printed music of identified or printed materials; 17 items. (Box-folder 67/3)
    - Covers of printed music containing publicity material with music; 4 items. (Box-folder 67/4)
    - Covers of printed music containing publicity material without music; 27 items. (Box-folder 67/5)
- II. Manuscript Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 68-75)
  The Manuscript Music Material series consists of holograph and copyist scores from the personal music library of Serge Diaghilev.
  Arrangement is by composer and title.
  - Bruguière, Émile
    - Le rêve de Lisette., Copyist's [holograph?] manuscript; reduced score, 97 p. (Box-folder 68/1)
  - Chabrier, Emmanuel
    - Une éducation manquée: Air d'Hélène., Copyist's manuscript; piano-vocal score; 7 p.; Language note: French; Contains 1 p. typed, photoreproduced lyrics (French); also contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 68/2)
  - Cimarosa, Domenico
    - [Arias; Duets.], Full score; copyist's manuscript; 278 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/18)
    - La felicità inaspettata: Quartetto., Strings/chamber ensemble; copyist's manuscript; 1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Il maestro di capella., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 44 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 68/4)
    - Il maestro di capella., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 40 p.; Incomplete; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 68/5)
    - Sonate., Harpsichord solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 22 p. (Box-folder 68/6)
    - La vergine del sole: Aria di Alci..., Strings or chamber emsemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 1 p.; Incomplete; title illegible; also includes (on verso): Paisiello, Giovanni.Il duello comico: [Excerpt]. Full score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. [incomplete]. (Box-folder 68/7)
  - Cleveland, Richard
    - Le necromancier., Reduced score; copyist's manuscript; 19 p.; Laid in: synopsis of the ballet's action, 1 p., typed. (Box-folder 68/8)
  - Crémieux, Octave
    - Quand l'amour meurt., Piano reduction; score; copyist's manuscript; 5 p.; Dated "Téhéran, 1932 Nov 9." (Box-folder 68/9)
  - Gounod, Charles
    - Philémon et Baucis: [Manuscript material]., Piano-vocal scores; copyist's manuscripts; 91 p.; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 68/10)
    - Philémon et Baucis: [Manuscript material]., Piano-vocal scores; copyist's manuscripts; 51 p.; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 68/11)
    - Philémon et Baucis: [Manuscript material]., Piano-vocal scores; copyist's manuscripts; 48 p.; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 68/12)
    - Philémon et Baucis: [Two fragments]., From piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscripts; Language note: Italian; Possibly holograph manuscript material of Georges Auric, who composed supplementary recitatives for the opera.; Autograph notation at top of one fragment contains directions (in French) to copyist "to copy 3 times." (Box-folder 68/13)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Piano-vocal scores of Act II, scene 13; copyist's manuscripts; six copies, 22 p. each.; These versions differ from that of the printed score.; Language note: French (Box-folder 69/1)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 102 p. each.; Language note: French; incomplete; This material is labelled "répétiteur" ("narrator"); duplicate pages are housed in clear polyester sleeves. (Box-folder 69/2)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 96 p.; incomplete; Language note: French (Box-folder 69/3)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for vn I; copyist's manuscripts; 66 p. (Box-folder 69/4)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for vn II; copyist's manuscripts; 48 p. (Box-folder 69/5)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for vla; copyist's manuscripts; 28 p. (Box-folder 69/6)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for vc, cb; copyist's manuscripts; 30 p.; 24 p. (Box-folder 69/7)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for fl, ob, cl, bn; copyist's manuscripts; 11 p.; 11 p.; 11 p.; 13 p. (Box-folder 69/8)
    - Le médecin malgré lui., Parts for hn, tpt, perc; copyist's manuscripts; 12 p.; 9 p.; 1 p. (Box-folder 69/9)
  - Graëfe, Gustave
    - Les roses d'Ispahan., Piano reduction; score; copyist's manuscript; 18 p. (Box-folder 70/1)
  - Méhul, Étienne Nicolas
    - La dansomanie: Ouverture., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 38 p.; incomplete after p. 38 (Box-folder 70/2)
  - de Montéclair, Michel Pinolet
    - Concerts [6] pour la flûte traversière avec la basse chiffrée., Score; copyist's manuscript; 87 p. (Box-folder 70/3)
  - Mozart, [Johann Chrysostom] Wolfgang Amadeus
    - Cassation, K. 63: Andante., Arranged for strings or chamber ensemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 7 p. (Box-folder 70/4)
  - Musorgskiĭ, Modest Petrovich
    - Khovanshchina., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 155 p.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 70/5)
    - Khovanshchina., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; in two sections (11, 23 p.), plus three unbound pages.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 70/6)
  - Paisiello, Giovanni
    - Achille in Sciro: [Excerpts, Act III]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 7 p.; Contains annotations in pencil on title page. (Box-folder 71/1)
    - Chaconne; Rigadon; Menuet., Strings and continuo or chamber ensemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 9 p. (Box-folder 71/2)
    - La finta amante: Act I., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 358 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/28)
    - Dal finto il vero: Sinfonia., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 7 p. (Box-folder 71/3)
    - Il duello comico., Full score; copyist's manuscript; [1] p.; incomplete: p. 1 only; Laid in: 1 p. copyist's manuscript, for piano solo. Scores bear inscriptions in Russian for the excerpts contained therein: side one reads "from the Concerto for clavicembalo...[illegible]."; side two (verso) reads "from the Rondeau from the Concerto for...[illegible]." (Box-folder 71/4)
    - Il duello comico: Air de Bettina., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 33 p.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 71/5)
    - Il duello comico See: Cimarosa, Domenico. La vergine del sole: Aria di Alci... Box 68, Folder 7
    - Gigue pour le Zéphir; Finale[to ?]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 51 p. (Box-folder 71/6)
    - Lucinda e Armidoro: [Excerpts]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; in two sections (3, 12 p.). (Box-folder 71/7)
    - Sei minuetti., Chamber ensemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 25 p. (Box-folder 71/8)
    - Sei minuetti., Chamber ensemble; copyist's manuscript parts for: vn I, vn II, ob I, ob II (3 p. each), hn I, hn II, continuo (2 p. each). (Box-folder 71/9)
    - Sei minuetti., Score; copyist's manuscript; 5 p. (Box-folder 71/10)
    - La modista raggiratrice: Finale, Act I., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 7 p.; incomplete; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 71/11)
    - Il mondo della luna: [Excerpts]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; in three sections (1, 15, 32 p.).; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 71/12)
    - Nina, o sia La pazza per amore: Cantata del pastore (?)., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 8 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 71/13)
    - Proserpine: [Excerpts from Acts I, II]., Full score; copyist's manuscript in two sections; 18 p.; 39 p.; Continuation of Act III section (p. 40) is on verso of p. 1 of La serva padrona: [Instrumental selections] (Box 71, Folder 19).; Incomplete (Box-folder 71/14)
    - Proserpine: [Excerpts]., Full score; copyist's manuscript in two sections (6, 10 p.). (Box-folder 71/15)
    - Raccolta di varie rondo e capricci., Piano solo with violin obbligato; score; copyist's manuscript; 11 p. (Box-folder 71/16)
    - Il re Teodoro in Venezia: Che novita! che stravaganza...; Come lasciar potrei., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 34 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 71/17)
    - La serva padrona., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 188 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/30)
    - La serva padrona: [Excerpt ("Il finale del manuscritto")]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 62 p.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 71/18)
    - La serva padrona: [Instrumental selections]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 23 p.; On verso of p. 1: end of Act III section (p. 40) of Proserpine: [Excerpts from Acts I, II]. (Box 71, Folder 14). (Box-folder 71/19)
    - Socrate immaginario: Ballo delle furie., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 3 p. (Box-folder 71/20)
    - Sonata a quattro mani., Piano four hands; score; copyist's manuscript; 14 p.; the last two pages contain autograph notes in Lifar's hand. (Box-folder 71/21)
    - Sonatine., Harpsichord or piano solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 22 p. (Box-folder 71/22)
    - [Unidentified work for piano solo.], Score; copyist's manuscript; in two sections (8, 9 p.). (Box-folder 71/23)
  - Pergolesi, Giovanni Battista
    - Andante Amoroso (Solfeggio no. 18)., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 5 p. (Box-folder 72/1)
    - Concerto., Violin and chamber ensemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 55 p. (Box-folder 72/2)
    - Euridice, e dovè sei?., Voice and chamber ensemble; full score; copyist's manuscript; 27 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 72/3)
    - Il flaminio: Aria di Ferdinando (Act II)., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 7 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 72/4)
    - Il flaminio: [Ballet following Act I.], Score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (recto and verso).; treble part only (Box-folder 72/5)
    - Il flaminio: [Ballet following Act II.], Score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (recto and verso).; treble part only (Box-folder 72/6)
    - Il flaminio: Duetto finale (Act I)., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 4 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 72/7)
    - Lo frate 'nnamorato: [Excerpts]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; in three sections (5, 21, 9 p.).; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 72/8)
    - Gavotta[?]: variazione 2, 3, 5., Keyboard solo; scores; copyist's manuscripts in three sections (2, 2, 2 p.). (Box-folder 72/9)
    - Il geloso schernito., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 109 p.; Language note: Italian; Language note: German (Box-folder 72/10)
    - Le maître de musique., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 80 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 72/11)
    - La serva padrona., Full score; copyist's manuscript; [121] p.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Italian; Numbered pages [missing p. 1-4], numbered on one side only (Box-folder 73/1)
    - La serva padrona[?]: Quello sdegno e quel furore., Piano-vocal score; copyist's manuscript; 5 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 73/2)
    - Solfeggi a due voci., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 13 p. (Box-folder 73/3)
    - Solfeggi a tre voci., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 108 p. (Box-folder 73/4)
    - Sonate no. 3: Allegro., Keyboard solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (Box-folder 73/5)
    - Sonate no. 6: Tempo di minuetto., Keyboard solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (Box-folder 73/6)
    - Sonate no. 7: Giga., Keyboard solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (Box-folder 73/7)
    - Sonate no. 7: Menuet., Keyboard solo; score; copyist's manuscript; 2 p. (Box-folder 73/8)
    - Sonate no. 10: [I.] Moderato., Two violins and continuo; score; copyist's manuscript; 5 p. (Box-folder 73/9)
  - Respighi, Ottorino
    - Recitativi per Le astuzie femminili di Cimarosa., Holograph piano-vocal score; [93] p.; In two sections p. 1-18 and p. 87-93; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 73/10)
  - Rimskiĭ-Korsakov, Nikolaĭ Andreevich
    - Snegurochka: [Excerpt (Act III)]., Vocal parts for SATB; copyist's manuscripts; 4 p.; 2 p.; 2 p.; 2 p. (Box-folder 73/11)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino
    - L'italiana in Algeri: [Excerpt (Act II)]., Full score; copyist's manuscript; 14 p.; incomplete after p. 14; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 73/12)
    - Il signor Bruschino: Sinfonia., Full score (67 p.) and parts for fl, ob I, ob II, cl I, cl II, bn, hn I (4 p. each), hn II (3 p.); copyist's manuscripts. (Box-folder 73/13)
  - Schumann, Robert
    - Papillons, op. 2., Arranged by N. Tcherepnin for orchestra; holograph [?] full score; 30 p. (Box-folder 82/1)
  - Stravinsky, Igor
    - Les noces., Copyist's manuscript part book (soprano/alto); 16 p.; Contains performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 74/1)
    - Les noces., Copyist's manuscript part book (tenor/bass); 15 p.; Contains performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 74/2)
    - Les noces., Copyist's manuscript part book (tenor/bass); 16 p.; Contains performance indications in pencil.; Contents: BOX: 74/4 Copy 2 of the above. BOX: 74/5 Copy 3 of the above. BOX: 74/6 Copy 4 of the above. BOX: 74/7 Copy 5 of the above. (Box-folder 74/3-7)
    - Les noces., Copyist's manuscript part book (tenor/bass); 17 p.; Contains performance indications in pencil.; Contents: BOX: 74/9 Copy 2 of the above. BOX: 74/10 Copy 3 of the above. BOX: 74/11 Copy 4 of the above. BOX: 74/12 Copy 5 of the above. (Box-folder 74/8-12)
    - Les noces., Copyist's manuscript part book (tenor/bass); 18 p.; Contains performance indications in pencil.; Contents: BOX: 74/14 Copy 2 of the above. BOX: 74/15 Copy 3 of the above. BOX: 74/16 Copy 4 of the above. (Box-folder 74/13-16)
    - L'oiseau de feu [=The Firebird]: Berceuse., Holograph manuscript in pencil with annotations in red pencil; 2 p. (recto and verso). (Box-folder S/59)
  - [Unidentified composer.]
    - Mazurka., Instrumental parts for vn I (5 copies), vn II (5 copies), vla I, vla II, vla III, vc I, vc II, vc III, cb I, cb II, fl, ob, cl, bn, hn, tpt (2 p. each); copyist's manuscripts. (Box-folder 75/1)
  - [Unidentified composer.]
    - The unconscious of Kathleen and Alistair., Full score; copyist's manuscript in 167 p. in five sections (11, 52, 32, 36, 36 p.).; Language note: English (Box-folder 82/2)
  - [Unidentified composer.]
    - [Unidentified], Contents: BOX: 75/2 Strings and continuo or chamber orchestra; full score; copyist's manuscript; [incomplete: p. 25-120 only]. BOX: 75/3 Full score (Italian); copyist's manuscript; 5 p. BOX: 75/4 [Unidentified manuscript material, 6 items.] (Box-folder 75/2-4)
- III. Personal Papers, 1750-1950 (Box 76)
  The Personal Papers series is divided into two subseries: Notebook and Correspondence. The Notebook series is represented by Diaghilev's personal notebook which the impresario used from 1926 until his death in 1929. The Correspondence series is represented by letters of Sergei Prokofiev and others.
  Arrangement is by format and by correspondent.
  - A. Notebook (Box-folder 76/1)
    - Autograph notebook of Diaghilev, dating from 1926 until his death in 1929; also contains entries in the hands of Lifar and Boris Kochno; entries are in French, Russian and English; c. 140 p. (Box-folder 76/1)
  - B. Correspondence (Box-folder 76/2-8)
    - Bauchant, André to Diaghilev; TLS and ALS receipt (French); dated 1928 Mar 30; 1, 1 p. (Box-folder 76/2)
    - Klemperer, Otto to Diaghilev; TLS (German); dated 1929 Jul 19; 1 p. (Box-folder 76/3)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergeĭ to Diaghilev; ALS (Russian); dated 1918 Oct 1; 1 p. (Box-folder 76/4)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergeĭ to Diaghilev; TLS and ALS envelope (Russian); dated 1922 Jun 26; 1, 1 p. (Box-folder 76/5)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergeĭ to Diaghilev; TLS (Russian); dated 1928 Sep 21; 2 p. (Box-folder 76/6)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergeĭ to Diaghilev; Photoreproduced copies of three letters, dated 1925 Nov 25; 1928 Apr 14; 1929 Aug 25 (Russian); 3 p. Gift of Mme. Prokof'eva. May not be photoreproduced. (Box-folder 76/7)
    - [Unidentified/notes.] Autograph (Russian, French); 4 p. (Box-folder 76/8)
- IV. Printed Material, 1750-1950 (Box 77-81, Box S/67-S/69)
  The Printed Material series is divided into five subseries: Libretti and Synopses; Books, Monographs, Programs, etc.; Serials; Photographs; and Miscellaneous.
  Arrangment is by format, composer and title.
  - A. Libretti and Synopses (Box 77-78)
    - Auber, Daniel-François-Esprit
      - Le premier jour de bonheur. Paris: Tresse, 1873., 86 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Adolphe d'Ennery and Cormon, Eugène (Box-folder 77/1)
    - Delibes, Léo
      - L'écossais de Chatou. Paris: Stock, 1910., 52 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Ad. Jaime and Gille, Philippe (Box-folder 77/2)
      - Kassya. Paris: Heugel, 1893., 75 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Henri Meilhac and Gille, Philippe (Box-folder 77/3)
      - L'omelette à la Follembûche. Paris: Stock, 1911., 46 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Eugène Labiche and Marc-Michel (Box-folder 77/4)
      - Six demoiselles à marier. Paris: Calmann-Lévy, 1883., 21 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by A. Choler (Box-folder 77/5)
      - Sylvia, ou la nymphe de Diane. Paris: Calmann-Lévy, n.d., 28 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Jules Barbier and Mérante (Box-folder 77/6)
    - Elukhen, Aleksandr
      - Sotra., Typed, photo-reproduced copy; 48 p.; Language note: Russian; Libretto by Genrikh Noeren after Arthur Conan Doyle (Box-folder 77/7)
      - Orphée., Typed, photoreproduced copy; 39 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Laura Finch (Box-folder 77/8)
    - Gounod, Charles
      - Mireille. Paris: Calmann-Lévy, n.d., 60 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Michel Carré (Box-folder 77/9)
      - Roméo et Juliette. Paris: Calmann-Lévy, n.d., 68 p.; Language note: French; Libretto by Jules Barbier and Michel Carré (Box-folder 77/10)
    - Holst, Gustav
      - The lure [=L'attirance]., Photoreproduction of typed copy; 8 p.; Language note: French.; Synopsis by Alice Barney. (Box-folder 78/1)
    - Méhul, Étienne Nicolas
      - Joseph. Paris: Calmann-Lévy, 1900; 37 p., Language note: French.; Libretto by Alexandre Duval. (Box-folder 78/2)
    - Migot, Georges
      - Agrestides., Photoreproduction of typed copy; 5 p.; Language note: French.; Synopsis by Louis Laloy and Georges Migot. (Box-folder 78/3)
      - Les aveux et les promesses., Photoreproduction of typed copy of synopsis; 3 p.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 78/4)
    - Mortier, Alfred [?]
      - Galatée., Typed synopsis; 12 p.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 78/5)
    - Paisiello, Giovanni